Benny Thomas

Mobile: 9968305144 Email: bennyt03@gmail.com

bennythomas.in

UX-UI Design & Development, Product Design, Consulting and Leadership for agencies, startups, and enterprises.

Summary:

An energetic design leader, specializing in UX-UI Design and Development. More than half a decade experience in understanding business objectives and delivering innovative UX-UI solutions. A proficient design leader and a critical thinker, I work within constraints while adapting to the unknown.

Experience:

Emediscene | UX-UI Lead & Veeva Certified Multichannel CRM Manager (Sept, 2017 – Present)

- Experience Design and UI Lead developing products for clients in the pharmaceutical industry
- Overseeing production and development of Visual Aids for iPads, Mobile experience design for medical products and services
- Building wireframes and low-fidelity & high-fidelity prototypes
- Built the information architecture and control flow for Avantor Rasayan App an app designed for distributers of lab equipments. App successfully launched and has over 100 users
- Successfully acquired company-wide certification for Veeva CRM
- Develop and manage content for closed loop marketing for client products via Veeva CRM
- Email marketing and secondary content development for various high-end medical products, instruments, and services
- Design and Technical consulting

Dignitas Digital | Senior Designer - Graphic & UX-UI (Aug, 2015 - Aug, 2017)

- User Experience Design & Interface Design Lead for clients of different industries
- Built information architecture and control flow for MyQ Tech App an interactive Q&A app for technology students, graduates, geeks and enthusiasts – now has more than 5000 users

- Develop wireframes using paper & pen or digital tools such as Illustrator and Balsimiq
- Building low-fidelity prototypes for early stage design and usability feedback from end users and management stakeholders
- Lead design development and information architecture
- Validating, analyzing, and defining design requirements, preparing user experience and information architecture models, creating and planning UI flows with specifications for web as well as mobile apps
- Formulate Design Standards to manage consistency across all platforms from design through development stage
- Manage aesthetic appeal of products, including developing custom icons and graphics
- Manage email design and development
- Lead design team for designing content for Digital Marketing team
- 2D animation for web and apps, whenever required, and GIF production

BGA | Designer - Graphic & UX-UI (May, 2011 - Jul, 2015)

- Founding member of a Design studio startup
- Design collaterals and other promotional and marketing materials for Print as well as Web
- Develop WordPress websites for various clients
- Graphic Design for social media campaigns and promotion
- Client servicing
- Content development

Alfred Allan Advertising | Copywriter (Jul, 2010 - May, 2011)

- Content creation and development
- Ideating for new concepts and campaigns
- Scriptwriting for corporate films and promotional campaigns
- Handle transcription and subtitling of various promotional films

IBM BPO, Mumbai | Team Leader - Email Communications (Aug., 2001 - May., 2005)

- Manage large teams for email customer support for various multinational corporations.
- Develop and nurture talent for leadership and management roles from within the team.
- English writing improvement workshops conducted and guidelines presented for effective communication.
- Studying the electronic medium and understanding psychology behind customer satisfaction and preparing strategies for improvement and quick turn-around times.

- Studying reports and forecasting trends.
- Preparing reports for internal reviews as well as client reviews.

Guess Info Systems | Web & Graphic Designer (Feb, 2001 – July, 2001)

- Website building and designing using Microsoft Frontpage
- Graphic Design and photo retouching to prepare quality images for websites

Awards:

- Acquired company-wide Veeva CLM Certification after just two weeks of onboarding. Received special recognition from the Veeva project Manager.
- Second runner-up award at Design Mela Contest 2015 held in Mumbai by Banana Bandy (now Indiefolio) and ISDI Parsons
- Employee of the Year 2016-17 at Dignitas Digital

Education:

- Pursuing Full Stack Development Freecodecamp.org
- Pursuing advanced Javascript Penn State University via edX.org
- Introduction to UX Design Coursera.org
- Certificate IV course in Aviation from Australia
- Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Aptech Ltd.
- B.A. English (Hons.) Ram Lal Anand College, Delhi University

Technical Knowledge:

Developer Skills:

- HTML5
- CSS3 | CSS Flexbox
- Bootstrap
- CSS Animations
- JavaScript | ¡Query
- Angular JS (familiar)

Creative tools:

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe XD
- Photoshop

- Dreamweaver
- Sketch
- After Effects

Prototyping Tools:

- Balsimiq
- InVision App
- Adobe XD

UX-UI Skills:

- Rapid prototyping
- iOS & Android App Design
- Information Architecture
- Content Strategy
- LEAN methodology
- Wireframing

Interests & Activities:

- Drawing and painting
- Writing short stories
- Playing table tennis, football, pool and snooker
- Reading books and design blogs
- Watching movies and TV series

Online Portfolio & Social Media:

- Website: bennythomas.in
- CodePen: codepen.io/bentom03/
- Twitter: twitter.com/bennythomas03
- Blog: medium.com/@bennythomas03